The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Purple Star Pavilion\NPurple Division of the\NHeavenly Fate Sect
All the powerful figures of Tian Yun
will come to celebrate Master's anniversary.
Master actually plans to publicly announce taking Wang Lin as his disciple...
What's so special about him !?
I have waited 2000 years
to become a Son of Tian Yun.
How could I possibly let him take my place ?
Second Brother Zhou Wan's cultivation was damaged
so he's out of the equation.
Third Brother Bai Wei is unpredictable
but he was never a match for me to begin with.
Fourth Sister Zhao Xinmeng has a good cultivation
but I have ways to deal with her.
Fifth Brother Jin Ye was punished by Master
to 100 years of secluded cultivation.
Sixth Brother Chen Tao has reached Ascendant
but he disappeared after Sun Yun took his place.
The only variable
is Wang Lin !
I noticed earlier today that
Seventh Junior Brother's cultivation
was significantly lower than when we first met on the trade planet.
You didn't need artifacts and spells to fight a Middle stage Soul Transformation.
Can you tell me why ?
No comments.
It's fine.
The more secrets,
the more intriguing.
Might I ask the purpose of Third Senior Brother's visit ?
You haven't collected your robes, identity token, and other items
so I brought them to you.
Thank you.
You are still unfamiliar with the Purple Division.
How about
letting your Senior Brother give you a tour ?
No need.
Seventh Junior Brother !
Don't you want to know why Senior Brother is targetting you ?
Or about what becoming a Son of Tian Yun
actually means ?
Every thousand years,
the sect will organize a competition to determine the Seven Sons of Tian Yun.
Whenever a position is vacant
or someone issues a challenge,
it leads to a duel.
2000 years ago,
Zhao Xingsha joined the Purple Division.
He was already Late stage Soul Transformation.
but during the competition,
he was injured by Sixth Junior Brother Chen Tao.
His cultivation plummeted.
He could only watch helplessly as Chen Tao became a Son of Tian Yun.
But Zhao Xingsha didn't give up.
He stubbornly cultivated for a 1000 years.
But during the last competition,
another Seventh Junior Brother, Sun Yun, emerged.
Both Zhao Xingsha and Chen Tao were defeated.
Sun Yun
then became the new Son of Tian Yun.
The next competition
is in 3 months.
Sun Yun betrayed the sect and fled.
The Purple Division's Son of Tian Yun has been vacant since then.
Chen Tao also left after he lost to Sun Yun.
We haven't heard from him
in 1000 years.
So you are his greatest opponent
in the next sect competition.
Titles are merely empty fame.
Why do they fight for it ?
Empty fame ?
The Seven Sons of Tian Yun are extremely noble.
They can
choose any country on Planet Tian Yun,
or even whole planets controlled by Tian Yun
as their own cultivation cave.
Is that all ?
Besides that,
Master will personally assist them during the Ascendant breakthrough,
increasing the chance of success by 30%.
He even provides the Seven Sons of Tian Yun with unlimited celestial jades.
Aren't you tempted ?
If you don't want empty fame,
to reach Ascendant,
or infinite celestial jades,
maybe you want celestial spells ?
If a Son of Tian Yun holds the title for 3000 years
Master will give them a low-grade celestial spell.
Long ago,
Ye Wuyou had obtained
a fragment of a low-grade celestial spell.
But it was incomplete
so we could only imitate it.
That's how I comprehended the three killing spells I just taught you.
If that was just from a fragment,
then a complete celestial spell
must be unimaginably powerful.
Since the collapse of the Celestial Realm,
celestial spells have disappeared.
Even fragments are hard to find.
It all depends on luck...
A low-grade celestial spell...
Is this true ?
Of course.
Why are you telling me this ?
Don't you want
one less competitor ?
I can't become a Son of Tian Yun
and you are the only rival Zhao Xingsha has
in the next competition.
I just want a single thing
and that's to prevent Zhao Xingsha from winning.
Only then
will I get my revenge for what he did back then !
Sorry,
I lost my composure.
I won't disturb you anymore today.
If you need anything,
Seventh Junior Brother can come find me anytime.
Bai Wei's personal grudge with Zhao Xingsha isn't my problem
but if what he said about celestial spells is true
then it's worth trying
to become a Son of Tian Yun.
The Heavenly Fate Sect is astonishing.
If direct disciples can get free celestial jades,
Treasure Pavilion\NPurple Division of the\NHeavenly Fate Sect
then it was worth the trouble to come here.
Disciple pays respects to Seventh Master.
This person carries
an extremely well-hidden Sword Spirit.
May I see
your flying sword ?
Of course.
Senior Zhou Yi's Sword Spirit !?
Back then, he left pursuing Sword Saint Ling Tianhou.
I haven't heard from him since.
How did a wisp of his Sword Spirit
end up here ?
Where did you get this sword ?
Seventh Master,
I bought this sword outside the sect.
It's just an ordinary item.
Is there a problem ?
This sword has a wisp of an old friend's Sword Spirit.
I will take it.
In exchange,
take this jade slip.
Use the 18 restrictions inside it
on your flying sword
and it will increase its strength
several times.
Thank you Seventh Master !
I came here
for celestial jades.
Seventh Master,
come in.
The Seventh Disciple of the Purple Division
hasn't withdrawn celestial jades for 103 years.
A total of 123 600 celestial jades.
Do you
wish to withdraw them all ?
Yes.
Celestial jades
withdraw !
Obtaining so many celestial jades just like that
solves the problem of how I will cultivate.
What kind of formation is this ?
I actually can't break it !
Forbidden spell...
Teleport !
Stone Forest\NOutskirts of the Heavenly Fate Sect
Fourth Senior Sister's teleportation spell
has really opened my eyes.
If Seventh Junior Brother is interested,
I can teach it to you
once everything is settled.
I'm here today on behalf of someone.
Please forgive me.
Zhao Xingsha...
Come out !
Seventh Brother,
just stay here and cultivate in peace.
I'll free you
when the time is right.
I'm the Third Disciple of the Blue Division,
Sima Rufeng.
Junior Brother Wang Lin,
I have heard
Sima Rufeng\NHeavenly Fate Sect Blue Division disciple\NLate stage Soul Transformation
of your name.
This guy's cultivation is above Fourth Senior Sister's.
He should be Late stage Soul Transformation.
Although he's not yet Ascendant,
Wang Yu\NHeavenly Fate Sect Green Division disciple\NLate stage Soul Transformation
he's not that far from it.
Are you afraid of me participating in the competition ?
I originally didn't consider you a threat.
But what happened yesterday,
I must admit
you
are my only rival in the Purple Division.
Senior Brother,
I have repaid the favor I owed you.
From now on,
we're even.
Everyone,
make your move !
How do you like the formation
I laid out for you overnight ?
Seventh Brother,
don't waste your efforts on the formation.
Once Master's birthday is over
and I've become a Son of Tian Yun,
I will naturally release you.
If I can't break this formation at Early stage Soul Transformation,
then I might be able to at Middle stage.
As long as I can reach Middle stage Soul Transformation within 3 months,
I will have a chance to escape this place.
You want to stop me from participating ?
How could I possibly let you !?
3 months later
Main Palace\Nof the Heavenly Fate Sect
Fellow cultivator !
Long time no see, fellow cultivator.
Long time no see !
Brother Zhao,
I hope you're well.
Please, take a seat.
Once the banquet begins,
we must share a few drinks.
Of course, of course.
Look !
Such a majestic chariot !
Yes !
Is that Senior Chi Lie ?
Chi Lie\NAll-Seer's Junior Brother\NNirvana Scryer
I must stand out
on Master's birthday.
All the powerful cultivators must know my name.
Once I become a Son of Tian Yun,
my path of cultivation will be smooth.
Paying respects to Master !
Paying respects to Senior All-Seer !
All-Seer,
this is your birthday gift.
I have lived for tens of thousands of years
do I really need birthday gifts ?
The fact that you have all come from afar
is the best gift of all.
There are banquets in each of the 7 divisions.
Everyone,
please have a seat.
Wang Lin's avatar\NMiddle stage Soul Transformation
Situ Nan told me
that with a higher cultivation,
the three killing spells will get stronger.
Let me see
how much this formation can withstand.
Death Finger !
Demonic Finger !
So it's not that strong...
Cao Yidou,
do you know the way
to the Heavenly Fate Sect ?
Yes.
We're celebrating Master's birthday today.
And tomorrow, Master will give a lecture on the Dao.
If our Purple Division
has been lacking in hospitality these past few days
I hope you will be excuse us.
I've heard that after the lecture,
there will be a competition for the Seven Sons of Tian Yun.
I think that
Brother Zhao has a high chance of winning.
You flatter me.
What's that ?
Is someone coming ?
Such a large commotion...
Are they hostile ?
Who dares to intrude in our Heavenly Fate Sect ?
How is this possible ?
It's just been 3 months.
Not only did he break free
but he also reached Middle stage Soul Transformation ?
Seventh Brother,
it's quite disrespectful of you to be late
at an important event
like this banquet.
He's the Seventh disciple of the Purple Division ?
Why is he late for Master's banquet ?
So disrespectful...
Senior Brother,
all you've done is messing with me
since I joined the Heavenly Fate Sect.
You've even gone to the extent
of seeking outside help to prevent me from coming today
by teleporting me away from the sect
and trapping me in the Stone Forest.
I, Wang Lin, have a principle.
If one doesn't mess with me,
I won't mess with them.
But if someone dares to mess with me
I will destroy them !
It wasn't properly explained how the All-Seer's disciples work.\NThe All-Seer has 7 true direct disciples known as the Seven Sons of Tian Yun (they actually weren't ever called like that in the novel but just called "true disciples").\NBut there is a total of 49 disciples of the All-Seer that lead each of the 7 divisions (that's what Wang Lin is right now). Below those are regular Heavenly Fate Sect disciples.\NIt's said that the Seven Sons of Tian Yun get infinite celestial jades and then it isn't really explained why Wang Lin fetches celestial jades. That's because there is a regular distribution of celestial jades to the All-Seer's disciples. Each one gets 100 celestial jades per month. But the jades are assigned by slot and the slot of the Seventh Purple Division disciple has been empty since Sun Yun left 103 years ago.\NThat astronomical number of celestial jades blows Wang Lin's mind. In the donghua he just like "Yeah cool I can cultivate now".\N\N\NWang Lin was startled. Even with his mental strength, he couldn’t help but be shocked. He took a deep breath and said, “I want to withdraw them all !”\N\N“A total of 123,600 pieces !” As the giant’s voice echoed, countless celestial jades flew out of the giant’s body and piled up before Wang Lin.\N\NWang Lin stared at the the pile of celestial jades as it rapidly grew and felt his throat dry up. He never would have thought that the Heavenly Fate Sect distributed celestial jades like this.\N“If a disciple spot remains empty for tens of thousands of years, then won’t the amount of celestial jades collect to an unimaginable degree ? Celestial jades are supposed to be rare, so why does the Heavenly Sect have so many…” Wang Lin took a deep breath. At this moment, the celestial jades had already formed a small mountain. His eyes lit up as he quickly put them into his bag of holding.\N\NAfter doing all of this, he touched his bag of holding. He still felt like none of this was real.
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?